<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Beginner on Ioannis Prapas</title><link>https://iprapas.github.io/categories/beginner/</link><description>Recent content in Beginner on Ioannis Prapas</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 29 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://iprapas.github.io/categories/beginner/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Easiest way to use Python virtual environments</title><link>https://iprapas.github.io/posts/python-virtualenv/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://iprapas.github.io/posts/python-virtualenv/</guid><description>Disclaimer: I know what you are thinking &amp;ldquo;That title is a clickbait&amp;rdquo;. I feel a little bit bad about it. But on second thought, I don&amp;rsquo;t have regrets.
It is the easiest way I know and I dare you to leave a comment if you know a better way.
What are virtual environments Instead of adding new python packages to your system installation, you add them to a virtual installation&amp;rsquo;s site-packages.</description></item><item><title>Remote Jupyter notebook locally over ssh gate</title><link>https://iprapas.github.io/posts/remote-jupyter-notebook/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://iprapas.github.io/posts/remote-jupyter-notebook/</guid><description>Problem I have encountered several times this problem:
Me: I want a nice interface to run python code in a remote machine.
Jupyter Notebook: I am here for you.
SSH Gate: I&amp;rsquo;ll make things trickier.
Well, here is the guide to setup a jupyter notebook server in a remote machine and connect to it, even if you need to pass through an ssh gate.
This guide is for UNIX-like systems and has been tested on Ubuntu 18.</description></item><item><title>Spam Classification with Spark MLLib</title><link>https://iprapas.github.io/posts/mllib-classification/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://iprapas.github.io/posts/mllib-classification/</guid><description>Disclaimer: This blog post will present my solution to an exercise of the Scalable Data Science offered by TU Berlin in winter semester 2019-2020.
Introduction In this exercise, we had to learn a model to classify spam, nospam SMS messages. We were given the SMS Spam Collection Data Set, split in 4 files:
training_spam.txt
training_nospam.txt
testing_spam.txt
testing_spam.txt
The goal is to train a model on the contents of the training* files and use it to predict the testing*.</description></item></channel></rss>